Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1904-1990 (Boxes 110-172)
  - Intellectuals
    - General. Edward S. Shapiro, "The Jewishness of the New York Intellectuals: Sidney Hook, a Case Study." Typescript and correspondence, 1988 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Miscellany. Syllabus, project proposal, notes, clippings, conference report, interview summary, mimeographed copy of Charles Kadushin, "How the American Intellectual Elite Decided to Oppose the War in Vietnam," typescript copies of Seymour Martin Lipset, "The End of Ideology and the Ideology of the Intellectuals" and Alan Wald, "The New York Intellectuals and World War II," and correspondence with Daniel Aaron, Albert Glotzer, Neil Jumonville, Mark Krupnick, William L. O'Neill, and Alan Wald, 1971-1988 (Folder 2-3)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, printed articles and excerpts, 1957-1987 (Folder 4)
  - Intelligence levels. Reprint, clipping, leaflets, television broadcast transcript, and letters, 1967-1976 (Folder 5)
  - International Congress for the Philosophy of Science. Reprint and typescript report, 1952-1954 (Folder 6)
  - International Congress of Philosophy. Program, by-laws, correspondence, and reports, 1947-1968 (Folder 7)
  - International Day against Dictatorship and War, Paris, Clippings, and correspondence with Claude Croutelle, 1949 (Folder 8)
  - International Freedoms Conference, 3d, Valley Forge, Pa., Brochures, programs, mimeographed copy of Frank R. Barnett, "Reclaiming the Initiative from the Soviet Heartland: The Case for a Tri-Oceanic Alliance of the Imperiled Rimlands," and letters, 1979 (Folder 9)
  - International Institute for Economic Research. Pamphlets issued by the International Institute for Economic Research, 1976-1978 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Iran. Letters, 1981 (Folder 2)
  - Iron Curtain Refugee Campaign. Correspondence with Charles P. Taft, 1949 (Folder 3)
  - James, William. Notes, proofs, letters, and reprints, 1964-1973 (Folder 4)
  - James vs. Board of Education of Central District No. 1. Legal briefs and decision, and letters by Harry Treinin, 1972-1974 (Folder 5-6)
  - Japan. Printed copy of Trade Union Movement in Japan (pamphlet), printed articles, clippings, correspondence with Melvin Lasky and others, translation of clipping, pamphlets, notes, serial issues, and anonymous typescript copy of "On Mother-Infant Interaction in Japan," and "Some Examples of JSP Use of Violence in the Diet and Disregard for Parliamentary Rules," and typescript copies of Juichi Katsura, "How Philosophy Stands in Japan at the Present," and "Der Weltbegriff im europaischen und orientalischen Denken," and Yoshihiko Seki, "The Concept of Democracy in Postwar Japan as Reflected in Magazine Articles,", 1949-1988 (Folder 7-8)
  - Jews and Jewish organizations. Press releases, notes, conference summary, clippings, pamphlets, printed article, serial issues, mimeographed material, mimeographed copies of Milton Friedman, "Capitalism and the Jews," and M. Mitin, "Zionist Agency of U.S. Imperialism," and correspondence with Werner Cohn, Abraham G. Duker, Elie Kedourie, Meyer Levin, Henry Mehlberg, Meyer Schapiro, Milton Steinberg and others
    - 1939-1946 (Folder 9)
    - 1947-1989 (Box 140, Folder 1-2)
  - Josephson, Matthew. Correspondence, 1977 (Folder 3)
  - Kafka, Franz. Correspondence, 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Kallen, Horace M. Reprints by Kallen, Lewis Feuer, and Milton R. Konvitz, and correspondence with Konvitz, J. B. Matthews and others, 1942-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Karier, Clarence J. Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 6)
  - Kazin, Alfred. Articles by Kazin, letters to the editor by others in reply, notes, and a letter by Hook, 1984-1988 (Folder 7)
  - Kempton, Murray. Pamphlet, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Kennan, George F. Printed articles and clipping, 1978-1986 (Folder 9)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeane. Printed articles and clippings by Kirkpatrick and others, press release, typescript copy of "Smith College's Dis-Honorary Degree" by Arnold Beichman, and letters by Jill K. Conway and Peter Gay, 1983-1986 (Folder 10)
  - Knopfelmacher, Frank. Clippings, serial issue, other printed matter, mimeographed material by Knopfelmacher and others, typescript copy of D. M. Armstrong and R. N. Spann, "The Rejection of Dr. Knopfelmacher's Application," and correspondence with Knopfelmacher and others, 1961-1971 (Folder 11-12)
  - Koestler, Arthur. Printed article, and correspondence with Martin Ebon, Lester Markel, Saul K. Padover and others, 1951-1984 (Folder 13)
  - Korea. Clippings, printed article, printed copy of U.S. Department of State, The Conflict in Korea (pamphlet), and correspondence, 1951-1985 (Folder 14)
  - Korsch, Karl. Serial issue, lecture notice, printed article, typescript copy of Karl Korsch, "Neuere Marxbiographische Literatur," and correspondence with Michael Buckmiller and another, 1932-1988 (Folder 15)
  - Kraus, Arthur J. Correspondence with Arthur J. Kraus and others, 1940-1969 (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Kuhn, Fritz. Printed letter, 1938 (Folder 2)
  - Labin, Edouard. Testimonial statements, and correspondence with Edouard Labin and others, 1952-1965 (Folder 3)
  - Labour and Socialist International. Printed copy of The Moscow Trial and the Labour and Socialist International (pamphlet), 1931 (Folder 4)
  - Lafargue, Paul. Mimeographed copy of Gerd-Klaus Kaltenbrunner, "The Red Apologist of Laziness,", 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Lamont, Corliss. Printed writings, memorandum, and letters by Lamont, clippings, notes, and correspondence with Roberta Dewey, William Gruen, Horace M. Kallen, Alfred Kohlberg, Eugene Lyons, J. H. Randall, Jr., Norman Thomas, Carlo Tresca, Peter Viereck and others, 1934-1988 (Folder 6-7)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon. Clipping and a printed copy of Nazis Without Swastikas: The Lyndon LaRouche Cult and Its War on American Labor (pamphlet issued by the League for Industrial Democracy), 1982 (Folder 8)
  - Lasch, Christopher. Letter, 1965 (Folder 9)
  - Laski, Harold J. Reprint, printed articles by Laski, printed copy of a letter from Oliver Wendell Holmes to Laski, and correspondence with Milton Hindus and others, 1922-1988 (Folder 10)
  - Lasky, Melvin J. Transcript of a speech by Melvin J. Lasky, clipping, printed article and letter, 1947-1987 (Folder 11)
  - Lattimore, Owen. Serial issues, clipping, and letter by Hook to Tom Wicker, 1954-1989 (Folder 12)
  - Law. Notes, clippings, proofs, printed articles, reprints, bulletins, speech by William Brennan, Jr., syllabi, broadcast transcript, and correspondence, 1947-1986 (Folder 13-14)
  - League for Industrial Democracy. Discussion transcript and correspondence, 1931-1983 (Folder 15)
  - Lefever, Ernest W. Correspondence with Lefever, Rudy Boschwitz, Alan Cranston, Jesse Helms, Charles Mathias, and Charles Percy, 1981 (Folder 16)
  - Lenin, V. I. Clippings, printed article and excerpt, publishers' announcements, mimeographed copy of David Shub, "Reply to Max Shachtman's Attack on Lenin: A Biography," notes, and correspondence with Shub and Walter Bedell Smith, 1931-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Lerner, Max. Printed article, clippings, and letters by Lerner and Hook, 1939-1947 (Folder 2)
  - Lewis, C. I. Notes, holograph outline, printed articles, and typescript copies of Raziel Abelson, "Knowledge and Memory," student papers, and letter, 1948-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Liberalism. Clippings, printed article, anonymous abstract entitled, "The Failure of Independent Liberalism, " and correspondence, 1946-1979, 1930-1941 (Folder 4)
  - Liberty. Printed articles, mimeographed copy of Stanley I. Benn, "Freedom and Persuasion," typescript copies of Kenneth Boulding, "American Leadership, Institutions, Choices, and Freedom," and Erich Rinner, "Planned Society and Individual Liberty," annotated copy of John Stuart Mill, On Liberty, notes, and correspondence, 1942-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Lippmann, Walter. Notes, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Literature. Notes, reprints, letters, and printed articles, 1932-1989 (Folder 7)
  - Logic. Notes, clippings, exercise, reprints, printed article, and letters by Martin F. Herz and others, 1938-1982 (Folder 8)
  - London, Jack. Correspondence, 1953 (Folder 9)
  - Lovejoy, Arthur O. Correspondence with Lovejoy and another, 1939-1979 (Folder 10)
  - Loyalty-security programs, 1947-
    - Correspondence with Herbert Abel, Alexander Baird, James Burnham, Howard W. Cannon, Midge Decter, William T. Hastings, Jean van Heijenoort, Daniel Lerner, Richard P. McKeon, David Martin, Richardson Preyer, Karl A. Wittfogel and others, 1947-1983 (Folder 11)
    - Miscellany. Leaflets, clippings, printed articles, reprints, statement, pamphlets, serial issues, printed excerpts, and note, 1947-1977 (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Lukacs, Georg. Printed articles, and correspondence with Zoltan Tar, 1977-1983 (Folder 2)
  - McCall, Lillian. Typescripts, report, memorandum, and correspondence, 1954-1957 (Folder 3)
  - Macdonald, Dwight. Correspondence with Michael Wreszin, 1987-1988 (Folder 4)
  - McGill, V. J. Correspondence with McGill, Paul Arthur Schilpp and others, 1938-1956 (Folder 5)
  - McGill Colloquium on Judaism and Human Rights, Montreal, Mimeographed conference papers by Salo W. Baron, "Civil versus Political Emancipation," Valery Chalidze, "The Perversion of Meaning in Civil Rights Discourse," Haim H. Cohn, "Equalities and Inequalities in Jewish Law," David Daube, "Human Rights," Yoram Dinstein, "How to DeUNize and Humanize the Protection of Human Rights," S. D. Goitein, "Human Rights in the Middle Ages," L. C. Green, "The Jew and Human Rights in the Twentieth Century," Ben Halpern, "Jewish Ethnicity," Rita E. Hauser, "International Human Rights Protection," Louis Henkin, "Reappraisal and Readjustment," Jacob Katz, "Jewish Emanicipation and Human Rights," Milton R. Konvitz, "From Jewish Rights to Human Rights," Sidney Liskofsky, "International Protection of Human Rights," Richard Mass, "Jewish Rights and the Democratic Movement in the Soviet Union," and Louis B. Sohn, "International Protection of Human Rights," 1974 (Folder 6-7)
  - Malaysia. Brochures, pamphlets, notes, and letter, 1969-1972 (Folder 8)
  - Mann, Thomas. Clippings, reprint, and correspondence with Karl A. Wittfogel and others, 1949-1954 (Folder 9)
  - Marcuse, Herbert. Clippings, printed articles by Marcuse and others, typescript copy of Milorad Drachkovitch, "Herbert Marcuse, The Intellectual Mentor of the International New Left," and Peter Fuss, "Herbert Marcuse," and correspondence, 1968-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Maritain, Jacques. Notes, printed articles by Jacques Maritain, and correspondence, 1939-1945 (Folder 11)
  - Marx, Karl
    - Correspondence with Stanley Burnshaw, Oscar J. Hammen, N. P. Jacobson, Paul Mattick, Kai Nielsen, Henry M. Pachter, Jules Sandock and others, 1932-1988 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Miscellany. Notes, holograph memorandum by Algernon Lee, mimeographed questionnaire by H. Leisegang, untitled typescript by Peter C. Ludz, typescript copy of G. A. Cohen, "Reconsidering Historical Materialism," and mimeographed copies of William F. Drischler, "The Theory of Oriental Despotism," and Michael Oakeshott, "Marx and the Nature of Political Discourse,", 1963-1982 (Folder 2-3)
    - Printed matter. Excerpts from writings by Marx and Friedrich Engels, printed articles, serial issues, pamphlet, press release, reprints, and letters, 1933-1984 (Folder 4-5)
  - Marx-Engels Institute, Moscow. Printed article, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Marxian economics. Printed articles, serial issue, and typescript copy of Abba P. Lerner, "Marxian Value, Surplus-Value and Surplus,", 1919-1963 (Folder 7)
  - Marxist Quarterly. Letters by Francis A. Henson, George Soule and another, 1936-1989 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Mass media. Clippings, pamphlets, bulletins, and correspondence with Edith Efron, Reuven Frank, Reed J. Irvine, James J. Kilpatrick, David Lichtenstein, Elmer W. Lower, Edwin Meese III, William Schneider, Eric Sevareid and others, Includes material relating to Accuracy in Media, 1939-1987. (Folder 2)
  - Mehnert, Klaus. Printed article, 1936 (Folder 3)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander. Printed and typescript writings by Alexander Meiklejohn, anonymous typescript reply to Meiklejohn, and correspondence, 1944-1960 (Folder 4)
  - Meiner, Richard. Pamphlet and letters, 1983 (Folder 5)
  - Menorah Journal. Correspondence, 1941-1989 (Folder 6)
  - Metaphysics. Reprints, serial issues, notes, and letter by Richard Gale, 1946-1989 (Folder 7)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo. Printed article, 1984 (Folder 8)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw. Letters, 1951-1953 (Folder 9)
  - Le Monde. Correspondence with Mario Einaudi, 1957 (Folder 10)
  - Moon, Sun Myung. Correspondence with Daniel Lerner and the U.S. Department of Justice, 1977-1985 (Folder 11)
  - Morgan, Lewis H. Reprints, 1944-1946 (Folder 12)
  - Morrow, Felix. Correspondence with Felix Morrow, Diana Trilling and another, 1979-1989 (Folder 13)
  - Moscow Trials, 1936-1937
    - General. Notes, clippings, printed excerpt, pamphlets by John Dewey and Leon Trotsky, press releases, speeches and statements by Dewey, Trotsky and others, typescript responses to allegations written by Trotsky, and typescript copies of Alan Wald, "Memories of the John Dewey Commission Forty Years Later" and "The Line of Blood,", 1935-1977 (Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Beard, Bruce Bliven, Malcolm Cowley, John Dewey, James Farrell, Albert Glotzer, Harold Laski (?), John MacDonald, Frederick L. Schuman, Herbert Solow, Alan Wald, Henry A. Wallace, Bertram D. Wolfe and others, 1937-1984 (Folder 16-17)
    - Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials
      - The Case of Leon Trotsky: Report of Hearings on the Charges Made Against Him in the Moscow Trials, Printed copy, 1937. (Box 146, Folder 1-3)
      - Not Guilty: Report of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, Printed copy, 1938. (Folder 4-5)
  - Mumford, Lewis. Printed articles and reprint by Lewis Mumford, 1931-1956 (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Munitz, Milton K. Correspondence with Milton K. Munitz and others, 1947-1957 (Folder 2)
  - Nagel, Ernest. Typescript writings by Nagel, bibliography, and letters, 1928-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Nation. Clipping, and correspondence with Arthur Krock, Margaret Marshall and others, 1950-1983 (Folder 4)
  - National Academy of Education. Membership rosters, minutes, bulletins, serial issue, and correspondence, 1968-1984 (Folder 5)
  - National Advisory Council on Education Professions Development. Report, and correspondence with Edward Shils and others, 1971-1975 (Folder 6)
  - National Council of Jewish Women. Bulletins, legal briefs, and correspondence, 1946-1957 (Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities
    - Applications for fellowships, 1973 (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with William Barrett, William Bennett, Ronald Berman, Jimmy Carter, Lynne Cheney, James Hester, Jacob K. Javits, Walter F. Mondale, Robert Nisbet, Richard M. Nixon, Paul Seabury and others, 1963-1987 (Folder 9)
    - Miscellany. Clipping, flyer, letter, notes, press releases, recommendations, statutes, reprint, minutes, memoranda, and report, 1966-1978 (Folder 10)
  - National Public Radio. Newsletter, notes, correspondence with Irving Kristol, Frank Mankiewicz, Nina Totenberg and others, 1981-1988 (Folder 11)
  - National socialism. Notes, clippings, serial issue, leaflet, and letter to Joseph Freeman, 1932-1934 (Folder 12)
  - Naturalism. Printed article, memoranda, mimeographed copy of Brand Blanshard, "The Limits of Naturalism," typescript copy of John Emil Troge, "The Law of Nature," and correspondence with Brand Blanshard, Ernest Nagel and another, 1944-1953 (Folder 13)
  - Near East. Pamphlets, serial issues, clippings, newsletters, and correspondence, 1943-1989 (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Nearing, Scott. Letter to William Bohn, 1959 (Folder 2)
  - Nelson, Leonard. Correspondence with L. H. Grunebaum, 1946 (Folder 3)
  - New Leader. Clipping and correspondence, 1951-1989 (Folder 4)
  - New School for Social Research. Lists of students and grades, examination questions, bibliographies, leaflets, and correspondence, 1932-1981 (Folder 5)
  - New York University. Pamphlets, clippings, minutes, speech, resolution, policy guidelines, memoranda, and letters, 1928-1988 (Folder 6-8)
  - New York University. Department of Philosophy. Memoranda, reports, miscellany, and correspondence with Max Black, Brand Blanshard, C. J. Ducasse, Carl G. Hempel, James Hester, Jacques Maritain, Anton C. Pegis, Walter T. Stace and others, 1936-1976 (Folder 9-10)
  - New York University. Institute of Philosophy. Announcements, and correspondence with Jacob A. Arlow, George E. Axtelle, C. J. Ducasse, Herbert Feigl, Heinz Hartmann, Lawrence R. Kegan and others, 1957-1976 (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - New York University. Jewish Culture Foundation. Correspondence, 1942-1952 (Folder 2)
  - New York University Press. Correspondence, 1949-1977 (Folder 3)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold. Notes, clippings, printed article, and correspondence, including a letter from Niebuhr to John Dewey, 1946-1986 (Folder 4)
  - Nielsen, Kai. Printed articles by Antony Flew and Kai Nielsen, mimeographed copy of Kai Nielsen, "Scepticism and Human Rights," typescript copy of Kai Nielsen, "On the Choice between Reform and Revolution," syllabi, bibliographies, examination questions, and letters, 1964-1974 (Folder 5)
  - Nixon, Richard M. Mimeographed copy of Perry Walsh, "That Sabbath Pardon," printed article, and inauguration program, 1973-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Nomad, Max. Promotional release, 1939 (Folder 7)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise. Printed articles by Conor Cruise O'Brien and others, clippings, and letters by Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., and others, 1961-1966 (Folder 8)
  - Obscenity. Printed articles by Morris D. Forkosch and others, 1964-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Ockham, William of. Printed article, 1963 (Folder 10)
  - Oppenheimer, Frank. Notes, and letters by Edward J. Rozek and another, 1965 (Folder 11)
  - Orlov, Yuri. Printed articles, and letters by Edward Oshins, 1982 (Folder 12)
  - Orwell, George. Letters, clippings, printed articles, and conference proceedings, 1984-1986 (Folder 13)
  - Parapsychology. Reprints, clippings, and correspondence with Theo Dore, Frank Olmstead, J. B. Rhine, Theodore Rockwell, Pasqual S. Schievella and another, 1950-1989 (Folder 14)
  - Partisan Review. Printed articles, clippings, mimeographed copy of Joseph Epstein, "Polonius Remembers: Neither a Communist nor an Anti-Communist Be," and correspondence with Epstein, Terry A. Cooney, S. A. Longstaff, William Phillips, and others, 1941-1989 (Box 150, Folder 1)
  - Peace. Clipping, reprint, bulletin, pamphlet, mimeographed copy of S. I. Hayakawa, "The Use and Misuse of Language: Some Thoughts on War and Peace," and correspondence with Leonard V. Fulton and others, 1949-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Peace and Freedom Party. Printed and mimeographed issuances of the Peace and Freedom Party, 1968 (Folder 3)
  - Peirce, Charles Sanders. Notes, reprints, leaflets, an untitled anonymous typescript and another entitled "Chapter Two: The Early Essays on Method, Meaning, and Truth,", 1932-1975 (Folder 4)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton. Reprint, printed copies of letters to the editor by Ralph Barton Perry and Albert A. Volk, and letter by William Henry Chamberlin, 1942-1954 (Folder 5)
  - Philosophy
    - Bibliographies, n.d., 1979 (Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1985 (Folder 8)
    - Examination questions, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Miscellany. Notes, announcements, poem, conference abstracts, an untitled mimeographed study by Rene J. Dubos, mimeographed copies of Michael Polanyi, "Tacit Knowing: Its Bearing on Some Problems of Philosophy," Richard Rorty, "Genteel Syntheses, Professional Analyses, Transcendentalist Culture," William Ruddick, "Chance and Causal Chains," Wilfrid Sellars, "Phenomenalism," and G. J. Warnock, "Verification and the Use of Language," and typescript copies of Antony Flew, "Philosophy and Political Action," and C. J. Ducasse, "What Reality Have the Past and Future?", 1932-1976 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Notes, n.d. (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter. Announcement, clippings, articles, printed excerpt, letters, and reprints
      - 1934-1974 (Folder 3-5)
      - 1976-1989 (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy, Oriental. Reprints, mimeographed copies of Yoshinori Takeuchi, "The Silence of Buddha," Hiromichi Takeda, "A Note on Nishida's Notion of 'Universal,'" typescript copy of Masaaki Hosaka, "The Philosophy of Kitaro Nishida," and letters by Subodh Chandra Roy, Che Ming-Zhou, and Walter T. Stace, 1956-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Philosophy, Russian
    - Miscellany. Mimeographed conference summary, and correspondence with George L. Kline and others, 1942-1963 (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter
      - General. Reprint, printed article, and serial issues, 1951-1982 (Folder 4)
      - Ost-Probleme. Issues of Ost-Probleme, 1956-1968 (Folder 5-6)
  - Podhoretz, Norman. Printed excerpt, proceedings, untitled typescript by Podhoretz, and letters, ca. 1979-1986 (Folder 7)
  - Poetry. Serial issue, syllabus, letter, and poems, 1957-1978 (Folder 8)
  - Poland. Printed copy of Oscar Lange, Poland and the United Nations, printed interview with Adam Michnik, clippings, serial issue, notices, and letters by Ginetta Sagan and Erazim Kohak, 1944-1989 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Polanyi, Michael. Reprint by Michael Polanyi, and clippings, 1953-1976 (Folder 2)
  - Political science. Notes, printed articles, clipping, and a typescript copy of Marion J. Levy, Jr., "Modernization Exhumed," and letters by John D., May, 1949-1984 (Folder 3)
  - Popper, Karl. Printed articles, reprint, clippings, and correspondence with Jonathan Lieberson and another, 1948-1988 (Folder 4)
  - Popular culture. Clippings, and leaflets, 1971-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Population. Chart, report, and letter, 1963-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Pragmatism. Notes, printed articles, serial issues, mimeographed copies of Gail Kennedy, "Pragmatism," W. V. Quine, "The Pragmatists' Place in Empiricism," and H. S. Thayer, "Pragmatism: A Reinterpretation," and typescript copy of Timothy V. Kaufman-Osborn, "The Democratic Promise of Pragmatism," and William E. Vandiveer, "Truth and Pragmatism," and correspondence, 1943-1989 (Folder 7-9)
  - Presidents - United States - Election
    - Correspondence with James Wechsler, 1964 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - 1972. Clippings, and correspondence with Leo Cherne, Joseph Clark, Elmer W. Lower and others, 1972-1973 (Folder 2)
  - The Proletarian. Printed articles, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Psychological warfare. Typescript copy of James Burnham, "Psychological Warfare or Else," printed articles, and letters by Boris Shub and another, 1945-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Psychology and behavior. Printed articles, printed resolution, flyer, mimeographed copies of John W. Copeland, "Philosophy Disguised as Science," Peter A. Corning, "The Biological Bases of Behavior and Their Implications for Political Theory," Lee J. Cronbach, "Beyond the Two Disciplines of Scientific Psychology," Clyde Hendrick, "Social Psychology as History: A Bibliography," Daniel Kahneman, "Cognitive Limitations and Public Decision Making," John Platt, "Social Traps," Michael Polanyi, "Problem Solving," Olaf Tollefsen, et al., "The Falsity of Determinism," and correspondence, 1935-1984 (Folder 5-7)
  - Puerto Rico. Pamphlet by Felix S. Cohen, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Rand, Ayn. Newsletters, serial issue, typescript copy of Ayn Rand, "The Objectivist Ethics," and letters by Barbara Branden and Ayn Rand, 1961-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Randolph, A. Philip. Correspondence, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Reconstructionist. Correspondence with Will Herberg and Milton R. Konvitz, 1949 (Folder 11)
  - Refugees. Report, typescript writings by O. Anisimov, list, and letters by Leopold Labedz and another, 1949-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Religion